Guide to the Gay Wilson Allen Papers, 1801-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accessions 95-095 and 95-100
  - Subject Files M-Z (Box 4)
    - Cratis Williams (Box 4)
    - Roger Williams (Box 4)
    - Tennessee Williams (Box 4)
    - Winters (Box 4)
    - Wordsworth (Box 4)
    - Zutawski. (Box 4)
  - Country Files A-G
    - Africa (South) (Box 4)
    - Austria (Box 4)
    - Belgium (Box 4)
    - Brazil (Box 4)
    - Britain (Box 4)
    - Bitish Isles (Box 4)
    - China, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Denmark (Box 4)
    - Finland (Box 4)
    - France (Box 4)
    - Germany (Box 4)
  - Country Files H-Z (Box 5)
    - Holland (Box 5)
    - Israel, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Italy (Box 5)
    - India, (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Japan (Box 5)
    - Latin America (Box 5)
    - Norway (Box 5)
    - Poland (Box 5)
    - Portugal (Box 5)
    - Russia (Box 5)
    - Spain (Box 5)
    - Sweden, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Yugoslavia (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Files
    - Activities (Box 5)
    - Articles for E.B. (Box 5)
    - Floyd Dell (Box 5)
    - Richard Ellmann (Box 5)
    - Encyclopedia Americana (Box 5)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 5)
    - D. Gimbel (Box 5)
    - Gregg (Box 5)
    - Guggenheim (Box 5)
    - R. P. Harriss (Box 5)
    - Harvard, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Hendricks (Box 5)
    - Hofstna (Box 5)
    - Jay Hubbell (Box 5)
    - William James, (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Leonard (Box 5)
    - Morrison (Box 5)
    - Noonday (Box 5)
    - Personal Bibliography, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Pessoa (Box 5)
    - Reprints (Box 5)
    - Rideout (Box 5)
    - Society of American Hist. (Box 5)
    - Suzuki (Box 5)
    - Whitcomb (Box 5)
    - Walt Whitman Birthplace (Box 5)
    - Who's Who (Box 5)
    - Zeiger (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, (8 folders) (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, (3 letter boxes) (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, (1 letter box) (Box 8)
    - Index Cards, (1 box) (Box 8)
      Literary references regarding Whitman and others.
    - Index Cards (4 boxes) (Box 9)
- Accession 96-062
  This unprocessed accession contains reprints of articles by Allen; research notes on William James, Walt Whitman, and Ralph Waldo Emerson; and drafts of writings on Whitman and others. The William James materials include transcripts of Alice James' diary, and other family letters and writings. Also included is a large portrait of Malcolm Cowley. Open for research.